<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>insight4health | Transforming data into strategic knowledge.</title>
    <description>insight4health is an iniciative created to provide high quality  information about  Mortality trends in Mexico.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 12:01:54 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 12:01:54 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reliable information to improve health care outcomes.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insight4health&lt;/strong&gt; provides a platform to analyze public health trends in Mexico. Currently Latin American countries represent a huge emerging market in terms of health care information. &lt;strong&gt;Insight4health&lt;/strong&gt; incorporates data science tools that transforms data from several sources, both public and private, into detailed input for acurate decision making.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generating evidence that contributes to design strategies to efficiently allocate resources is a permanent task that is relevant particularly when dealing with high cost diseases. Having access to reliable information becomes key to achieve this goal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;unleash-data-science-potential-to-analyze-public-health-patterns&quot;&gt;Unleash data science potential to analyze public health patterns.&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We incorporate a data...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 12:17:18 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/The-market-value-of-health-information/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/The-market-value-of-health-information/</guid>
        
        <category>Big data</category>
        
        <category>Public Health</category>
        
        <category>Healh economics</category>
        
        <category>Data Sciences</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>20 years of Type II Diabetes mortality at Mexican border states.</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite the importance of geographic location to explain this epidemic, in the past decades the study of biological risk factors has been the dominant paradigm (Graves and Kayal, 2008; Stolar 2010).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although diabetes is a major public health problem in &lt;strong&gt;Mexico&lt;/strong&gt; previously thought to be related to population with relative higher income levels or affluent, recent studies had suggested an epidemiological transition impacting individuals in lower income regions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Studies conducted with a focus on the Mexican population suggest that this transition may be linked to nutritional changes (Seuring, Goryakin &amp;amp; Suhrcke, 2015). Argument that highlights the importance to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Diabetes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Diabetes/</guid>
        
        <category>Chronic</category>
        
        <category>Epidemics</category>
        
        <category>Diabetes</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Public health expressions in the  context of Mexican urban expansion.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;Rhinitis&lt;/strong&gt; describes a disease characterized by an inflammation of the nasal mucosa. Unleashed by an immune system overreaction against particular trigger factors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Symptoms can evolve taking a chronic or acute pattern. As well as appear in an intermittent fashion (Rombaux &amp;amp; Hellings 2014).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Complications related to this health condition in the group of chronic inferior respiratory airways problems, include diseases with a high impact on life quality of the family as well as considered as high management cost such as allergic asthma, &lt;strong&gt;(J450)&lt;/strong&gt; (Gutiérrez-Cardona et al. 2017).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Or comorbidities that affect superior airways including diseases such as chronic...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Rhinitis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Rhinitis/</guid>
        
        <category>Air quality</category>
        
        <category>Pollution</category>
        
        <category>Rhinitis</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Suicide Mortality in México. studying Territorial Patterns.</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Too often health professionals are focused on what is simpler, that is treat a medical or mental illness, whereas facing suicide risk goes beyond the traditional approach and involves human understanding of suffering.”&lt;/em&gt; Maurizio Pompili. 2018&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;During the last 20 years, suicide as a death cause in Mexico, reach a 74.8% growth, which translates into a 3.74% annual increase rate. This pattern surpassed by 60% the dynamics observed by the overall causes of death.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This report documents Mexico´s suicide evolution in time during the period 1998-2017 with a focus on &lt;strong&gt;Aguascalientes&lt;/strong&gt; State. The methodology is based on exploratory...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Suicide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Suicide/</guid>
        
        <category>Mental Health</category>
        
        <category>Depression</category>
        
        <category>Google Trends</category>
        
        <category>Suicice</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Newborn Respiratory Distress Syndrome.</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;It appeared as if Hercules was the father, thought Bennewitz in 1824, when delivering the giant foetus of a diabetic woman. &lt;strong&gt;H. G. Bennewitz, 1924&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;During 2016, in Mexico there were 82 764 newborn babies diagnosed with birth defects, in a range of 797 different diseases. Although 51% of the cases concentrated in just 10 different causes, respiratory distress syndrome of newborn (ICD code: P220) represent the third highest frequency cause in the country with 4 996 cases.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This report documents the geographic distribution of the Newborn Respiratory Distress Syndrome (NRDS) cases as well as their time evolution...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Respiratory-Distress-Syndrome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Respiratory-Distress-Syndrome/</guid>
        
        <category>Respiratory distress Syndrome</category>
        
        <category>Newborn</category>
        
        <category>Diabetic mother</category>
        
        <category>Newborn health</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coccidioidemycosis in Mexico.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite that several research initiatives has referred to the link between health and environment as “the greatest global health opportunity of the 21st century” (Wang y Horton, 2015), in Latin American countries such as México, there are still scarce efforts to tackle this important challenge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This study shows the temporal dynamics of &lt;strong&gt;coccidioide mycosis&lt;/strong&gt; in Mexico, during the period between 2004-2015 in the context of its socio-environmental determinants and identifies its actual distribution in the national territory by means of the construction of geographical concentration indicators.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An exploratory analysis of data was made from micro data on &lt;strong&gt;hospital discharges&lt;/strong&gt; in...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/coccidiodemycosis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/coccidiodemycosis/</guid>
        
        <category>Coccidioide  mycosis</category>
        
        <category>Sonora</category>
        
        <category>Environmental health</category>
        
        <category>Coccidioidemycosis</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spatial and temporal Expressions of chronic Kidney Disease in Mexico</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Given the recent growth trend by &lt;strong&gt;chronic diseases&lt;/strong&gt; taken place in some &lt;strong&gt;Latin American countries&lt;/strong&gt; such as Mexico, conducting research using a spatial approach is consider as a relevant way to provide insight into this public health treat.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;CDK treatment include high cost procedures such as hemodialysis or in advanced stages a need for transplants, thus contributing to understand Chronic kidney disease determinants is considered a relevant area of research with great social benefits.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The aim of this report is to study the temporal and spatial pattern of chronic renal disease in Mexico during the last decade, explicitly...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/CKD/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/CKD/</guid>
        
        <category>renal disease</category>
        
        <category>water quality</category>
        
        <category>Kidney</category>
        
        <category>Renal Failure</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Geospatial approach to the social determinants of Cancer.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is important to better understand &lt;strong&gt;cancer&lt;/strong&gt; dissemination and its &lt;strong&gt;geographic patterns&lt;/strong&gt;. The study of its &lt;strong&gt;spatial distribution&lt;/strong&gt; can contribute to implement target preventive and control strategies allowing a reduction of the social cost and financial burden for the health care system.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Social determinants of economic origin such as income levels or consumption patterns are two research areas of concern. Income conditions are a key component of poverty which in turn influence health care access mechanisms such as early detection, treatment options and management decisions. In the other hand, consumption patterns represent a latent exposure mechanism to compounds and...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 15:55:45 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cancer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cancer/</guid>
        
        <category>Cancer</category>
        
        <category>Consumption patterns</category>
        
        <category>Social Determinants of Health</category>
        
        <category>Cancer</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mortality due to hypertensive diseases.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last decade, hypertensive diseases in Mexico has shown an increasing pattern that reveals a pubic health issue of concern with growing cost. This upward trend is particularly important in specific regions of the country such as the southern border, a region comprised by five states: Chiapas, Campeche, Quintana Roo, Yucatán y Tabasco.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This report analyzes patterns of mortality due to &lt;strong&gt;hypertensive diseases&lt;/strong&gt; in the southern border of Mexico, as well as the evolution of such mortality in the 1998-2014 period.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hypertension is defined as a condition where a sustained increase in the blood pressure takes place, with...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 16:04:08 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Hypertension/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Hypertension/</guid>
        
        <category>Hypertension</category>
        
        <category>Indigenous population</category>
        
        <category>diet</category>
        
        <category>Hypertension</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Viral infection from mosquito bites in Mexico in the period 2004-2014.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While viral infections transmitted by mosquito bites are not a new phenomenon, until recently, this kind of health treat has been acquiring particular importance considering its rapid expansion and its apparent link to some serious neurologic manifestations observed in conditions as those produced by *Zika virus**, a health condition that was declared an international public health emergency.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is not yet an antiviral approved for Vector-borne diseases such as Zika virus, so preventive measures can help reduce the negative impacts on the population of this peculiar disease.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;This report aims to determine the spatial distribution of hospital discharges...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 06:24:49 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/smoke-alert/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/smoke-alert/</guid>
        
        <category>Zika</category>
        
        <category>Vector-borne</category>
        
        <category>Aedes aegypti</category>
        
        <category>Zika virus</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do you believe that a spider can dance?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cas sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-html-elements&quot;&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Zika/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Zika/</guid>
        
        <category>fate</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A cook cries in the rain at night</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cas sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-html-elements&quot;&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-cook-cries-in-the-rain-at-night/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-cook-cries-in-the-rain-at-night/</guid>
        
        <category>cook</category>
        
        <category>cucine</category>
        
        <category>story</category>
        
        <category>diet</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grab your band and get out</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cas sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-html-elements&quot;&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/grab-your-band-and-get-out/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/grab-your-band-and-get-out/</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>band</category>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Passion is dangerous, go for it!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cas sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-html-elements&quot;&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/passion-is-dangerous-go-for-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/passion-is-dangerous-go-for-it/</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Birds can fly, but this you knew already</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cas sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-html-elements&quot;&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 05:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/birds-can-fly-but-this-you-knew-already/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/birds-can-fly-but-this-you-knew-already/</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>tips</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
